Guide to the University of Hartford Studies in Literature ARCH031
University of Hartford Archives & Special Collections
University of Hartford Studies in Literature collection
1967 - 1991
University of Hartford Archives & Special Collections
University of Hartford
ARCH031
2.58 Linear Feet (13 containers total - 3 boxes and 10 bound books)
Conditions Governing Access
The collection is open to all researchers.
Existence and Location of Copies
Some earlier issues have been digitized and are available here: http://mdid3b.hartford.edu/explore/explore/?c=allcollections:74. Access to the digital repository is limited to the University of Hartford Campus. Computers are available to the public at the Harrison Libraries.
Biographical / Historical
From 1969 to 1977 the publication was known as Hartford Studies in Literature (HSL), until 1977 when the publication changed to University of Hartford Studies in Literature (UHSL).
Scope and Contents
This collection contains every issue of the University of Hartford Studies in Literature (UHSL) from 1969 - 1991, as well as a few memorandums, press releases, clippings, and a photograph.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged chronologically.
Literature -- History and criticism; Periodicals; University of Hartford
- Memorandums, Correspondence, and Press, 1967 - 1977 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Photograph, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Issues, 1969 - 1991
  - Hartford Studies in Literature, Vol. 1, No. 1, 1969 (Object Bound book vol. 1-3, Box 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Volume 1, Number 1. Front Matter (pg. 1); 2001 and the Paradox of the Fortunate Fall, BY ALAN BRODY (pg. 7); 2001: A Psychosocial Explication, BY NORMAN N. HOLLAND (pg. 20); Sons and Fathers, A.D. 2001, BY ROBERT PLANK (pg.26); The Psychology of the 'Double' in 2001, BY ROBERT ROGERS (pg. 34); A Plurality of After-Worlds: Isaac Taylor and Alfred Tennyson, BY MILTON MILLHAUSER (pg. 37); Some Literary Uses of Numerology, BY JOHN T. SHAWCROSS (pg. 50); Book Review, Humans and Humanoids, BY MARVIN REZNIKOFF (pg. 63); Book Notes (pg. 68).
  - Hartford Studies in Literature, Vol. 1, No. 2, 1969 (Object Bound book vol. 1-3, Box 1)
    Volume 1, Number 2. Front Matter (pg. 69); Natural Fact and Poetic Insight, BY FREDERICK PLOTKIN (pg. 71); Perception as a Form of Phenomenological Criticism, By DAVID I. GROSSVOGEL (pg. 83); "A Portrait of 'Jenny'": Rossetti's Aesthetics of Communion, BY JAN B. GORDON (pg. 89); Mrs. Radcliffe's Landscapes: The Influence of Three Landscape Painters on her Nature Descriptions, By LYNNE EPSTEIN (pg. 107); Illustrations: Plate I. The Awakening Conscience, Holman Hunt (pg. 111); Plate II. The Blessed Damozel, Dante Gabriel Rossetti (pg. 112); Plate III. Dantis Amor, Dante Gabriel Rossetti (pg. 112); Plate A. Night Scene with Figures ? The Banditti, Salvator Rosa (pg. 113); Plate B. St. George and the Dragon, Claude Lorrain (pg. 114); Plate C. Landscape with a Man Killed by a Snake, Nicolas Poussin (pg. 114); Is Football Playing?, BY GEORGE T. WRIGHT (pg. 121); Cinematic Thought, BY PAUL STACY (pg. 124); 2001: Years and Shapes, BY VICTOR A. DOYNO (pg. 131); Comment, BY ROBERT R. FENICHEL (pg. 133); A Belated Justification, By NORMAN N. HOLLAND (pg. 136); A New Look at Hemingway, BY RICHARD W. NOLAND (pg. 140); Friends and Relations, BY ELEANOR AND LEONARD MANHEIM (pg. 146); Books, Journals, and Offprints Received (pg. 156).
  - Hartford Studies in Literature, Vol. 1, No. 3, 1969 (Object Bound book vol. 1-3, Box 1)
    Volume 1, Number 3. In Memoriam: Gorham Munson (pg. 162); Woodstock, 1924, BY GORHAM MUNSON (pg. 169); Woodstock, 1969, BY WILLIAM CLEMENT (pg. 181); The "Professional" Clergyman in Some Novels by Anthony Trollope, BY FREDERICK F. JILLSON (pg. 185); Trollope's Clerical Concerns: The Low Church Clergymen, BY JAMES W. LEE (pg. 198); Gilbert and Sullivan Songs in the Works of James Joyce, BY MABEL P. WORTHINGTON (pg. 209); Early Psychological Criticism, BY RICHARD W. NOLAND (pg. 219); Tragic Comic Punster and Pimdit, BY THOMAS L. ASHTON (pg. 223); Books, Journals, and Offprints Received (pg. 230).
  - Hartford Studies in Literature, Vol. 2, No. 1, 1970 (Object Bound book vol. 1-3, Box 1)
    Volume 2, Number 1. The Iconography of David Copperfield, BY MICHAEL STEIG (pg. 1); Emblems in Victorian Literature, BY JOHN R. REED (pg. 19); Blake's Illustrations for Paradise Lost, L'Allegro, and II Penseroso: A Thematic Reading, BY EDWARD J. ROSE L (pg. 40); Yeats's Dualities: Two Restatements, BY PAUL H. STACY (pg.68); Psychoanalysis and Judaism, BY RICHARD W. NOLAND (pg. 70); The Uses Of Imaginative Reason, BY RICHARD W. NOLAND (pg. 75); The Political and Intellectual Milieu of Tudor Drama, BY MICHAEL MANHEIM (pg. 85); Puritanism and Milton, BY HAROLD P. LEVITT (pg. 92); Books, Journals, and Offprints Received (pg. 94).
  - Hartford Studies in Literature, Vol. 2, No. 2, 1970 (Object Bound book vol. 1-3, Box 1)
    Volume 2, Number 2. Front Matter (pg. 99); Heart Transplant Fiction, By ROBERT PLANK (pg. 102); Metamorphosis of a Malady: Sxmimary of a Psychoanalytic Study of Emily Dickinson, By JOHN CODY (pg. 113); "The Tangle of Life": Levels of Meaning in The Spoils of Poynton, BY ARNOLD EDELSTEIN (pg. 133); Jason Compson's Paranoid Pseudocommunity, BY CHARLES D. PEAVY (pg. 151); Faulkner's Spotted Horses, BY J. REA (pg. 157); Ecology in The Grapes of Wrath, BY JACK NIMITZ (pg. 165); Dreiser's The "Genius": Motivation and Structure, BY RICHARD B. HOVEY AND RUTH S. RALPH (pg. 169); Pope and Science, BY RICHARD W. NOLAND (pg. 184); Intellectual Movements in History, BY FREDERICK W. TURNER, III (pg. 188); Books, Journals, and Offprints Received (pg. 192).
  - Hartford Studies in Literature, Vol. 2, No. 3, 1970 (Object Bound book vol. 1-3, Box 1)
    Volume 2, Number 3. The Multiple Murders of Therese Desqueyroux, BY C. FREDERICK FARRELL, JR., AND EDITH R. FARRELL (pg. 195); The Mother in Frangois Mauriac's Genitrix, BY JAMES P. MCNAB (pg. 207); Italo Svevo: The Vocation of Old Age, BY C. ROLAND WAGNER (pg. 214); The "Cosmonauts' Song" in Diirrenmatt's Physicists, BY GEORGE C. FOREST (pg. 229); Rhetoric and Musical Form: Johann Adolph Scheibe's Schreibarten, BY IMANUEL WILLHEIM (pg. 238); Literature and Theology, BY RICHARD W. NOLAND (pg. 248); The Anthropology of Literature, BY SALLY N. LA WALL (pg. 256); Aldous Huxley's Stereoscopic Vision, BY DONALD J. WATT (pg. 263); NOTES ON THIS ISSUE (pg. 270).
  - Hartford Studies in Literature, Vol. 3, No. 1, 1971 (Object Bound book vol. 1-3, Box 1)
    Volume 3, Number 1. Mannerist Frivolity and Shakespeare's Venus and Adonis, BY GORDON ROSS SMITH (pg. 1); Easy Rider: Touching the Tragic, BY NORMAND BERLIN (pg. 12); Robbe-Grillet's La Jalousie and a Parallel in the Graphic Arts, BY MAURICE A. LECUYER (pg. 19); Hiroshima Mon Amour — Revisited, BY ALFRED QSMARU (pg. 39); Self-Unification: An Archetypal Analysis of Prospero in The Tempest, BY ANSON C. FYLER, JR (pg. 45); Poetry and Tradition, BY RICHARD W. NOLAND (pg. 51); Multiple Psychoanalytic Approaches, BY MELVIN GOLDSTEIN (pg. 55); D. H. Lawrence and Men in Love, BY PAUL H. STACY (pg. 59); Five Modem French Writers, BY J. E. FLOWER (pg. 61); Books, Journals, and Offprints Received (pg. 64-72).
  - Hartford Studies in Literature, Vol. 3, No. 2, 1971 (Object Bound book vol. 1-3, Box 1)
    Volume 3, Number 2. Circumstance, Circumference, and Center: Immanence and Transcendence in Emily Dickinson's Poems of Extreme Situations, BY ZACHARIAS THUNDYIL (pg. 73); The Diary of John Adams and the Motive of "Achievement", BY STEVEN EARL KAGLE (pg. 93); The Theory of Relativity and The Bridge, BY JAMES C. COWAN (pg. 108); Miss Lonelyhearts: A Dual Mission of Mercy, BY RICHARD GEHA (pg. 116); Contemporary Psychoanalytic Criticism, BY RICHARD W. NOLAND (pg. 132); Defining American Romance, BY A. W. PLUMSTEAD (pg.144); Words For Hart Crane, BY PAUL L. MARIANI (pg. 150); The Man Who Died Twice, BY ELLSWORTH BARNARD (pg. 154).
  - Hartford Studies in Literature, Vol. 3, No. 3, 1971 (Object Bound book vol. 1-3, Box 1)
    Volume 3, Number 3. The Dynamics of Metaphor: Modes of Mentation in Poetry, By Robert Rogers (pg. 157); Metaphysical Poetry as Event, Richard E. Hues (pg. 191); Dostoevski's Kirilov and Freedom of the Will, By Stephen A. Reid (pg. 197); On Victorian Illustration, By John R. Reed (pg. 209); The Buffalo School of Psychoanalytic Critics, By Leonard Manheim (pg. 213); Books, Journals, and Offprints Received (pg. 219).
  - Hartford Studies in Literature, Vol. 4, No. 1, 1972 (Object Bound book vol. 4-5, Box 1)
    Volume 4, Number 1. Fantasy and Defense in Faulkner's "A Rose for Emily", By Norman Holland (pg. 1); The Two Boyhoods, By Milton Millhauser (pg. 36); Donne's Divine Rapist: Unconscious Fantasy in Holy Sonnet XIV, By Michael Steig (pg. 52); The Stranger and Camus' Transcendental Existentialism, By Joyce Albrecht (pg. 59); Oscar Wilde: The Critic as Reviewer, By Robert Keefe (pg. 81); A Look at the Speaker, By Morris Golden (pg. 87).
  - Hartford Studies in Literature, Vol. 4, No. 2, 1972 (Object Bound book vol. 4-5, Box 1)
    Volume 4, Number 2. Death in Venice: Tragedy or Mishap?, By Robert Plank (pg. 95); Great Expectations: Dicke'ns' Style in Terms of Film, By Ana Laura Zambrano (pg. 104); Alice among the Analysts, By Paula Johnson (pg. 113); The Incredible String Band and Robin Williamson's "Creation", By Sheldon Brivic (pg. 123); The Social-Christian and Christian-Social Doctrines of Samuel Richardson, By Richard Cohen (pg. 135); Wordsworth's Healing Power: Basic Trust in "Tintern Abbey", By Leon Waldoff (pg. 147); Faustus Now, By Meredith Gary (pg. 167); A Psychiatric Look at Emily Dickinson, By Eleanor Lyons (pg. 174); Satragraya and Ahimsa, By Eleanor B. Manheim (pg. 180); Finding the Fifth Dimension, By Virginia Shea Noto (pg. 183).
  - Hartford Studies in Literature, Vol. 4, No. 3, 1972 (Object Bound book vol. 4-5, Box 1)
    Volume 4, Number 3. Front Matter (pg. 186); Arcana; Mo Hoy, Malone Dies, The Unnamable: A Brief Comparison of Forms, by James Conely (pg.187); The Limits of Qarity: Lyly's Endymion, Bronzino's Allegory of Venus and Cupid, Webster's White Devil, and Botticelli's Primavera, By Doris Brenan Braendel (pg.197); Dante Gabriel Rossetti: The Synthesis of Picture and Poem, by M. K. Bequette (pg. 216); D. G. Rossetti: Love, Death and Art, by Janet Warner (pg. 228); Oedipal Patterns in Stendhal, by Eleanor B. Manheim (pg. 241); Whither T. H.?, by David H. Paroissien (pg. 245); Faint Praise, by Nancy Walker (pg. 251); Books, Journals, and Offprints Received (pg. 259).
  - Hartford Studies in Literature, Vol. 5, No. 1-3, 1973 (Object Bound book vol. 4-5, Box 1)
    Volume 5, Number 1,2,3. Introduction; The Space in Psychological Criticism, By Murray Schwartz (pg. x); To Leonard Manheim on his 70th Birthday, By Melvin Goldstein (pg. 1); Tabula Gratulatoria (pg.2); A Letter to Leonard, By Norman N. Holland (pg. 9); Analytic Prolegomena to the Study of Western Tragedy, By Melvyn D. Faber (pg. 31); A Gathering of Roses, By Robert Rogers (pg. 61); Abandoned in Providence, By William J. Wasserstrom (pg. 77); The Future of Psychological Clriticism, By Richard V. Noland (pg. 88); Poe's Intimations of Mortality, By Louis B. Fraiberg (pg. 106); Psychological Realism and Fantasy in Jane Austen: Emma and Mansfield Park, By Michael Steig (pg. 126); In Death They Were Not Divided: The Moral Magnificence of Unmoral Passion in Wuthering Heights, By Wayne Burns (pg. 135); " The Cross-Grainedness oœ Men ": The Rev. Josiah Crawley- Trollope's Study of a Paranoid Personality, By Helen Storm Corsa (pg. 160); Index to Volumes I ? V (pg. 173).
  - Hartford Studies in Literature, Vol. 6, No. 1, 1974 (Object Bound book vol. 6-7, Box 1)
    Volume 6, Number 1. Calderdn's Life is a Dream: From Psychology to Myth, By Gisele Feal and Carlos Feal-Deibe (pg. 1); "The Wall ": Sartre's Metaphysical Trap, By Rebecca E. Pitts (pg. 29); The Magic Square: Polar Unity in Thomas Mann's Doctor Faustus, By Robert Magliola (pg. 55); The Psychological Criticism of Norman N. Holland, By Richard W. Noland (pg. 72); Lear Unmasked, By Miriam Gilbert (pg. 80); 1973 Bibliography on the Relations of Literature and Other Arts, By The Bibliography Committee of MLA General Topics IX (pg. 87); Index to Volumes I - V (Errata) (pg. 108).
  - Hartford Studies in Literature, Vol. 6, No. 2, 1974 (Object Bound book vol. 6-7, Box 1)
    Volume 6, Number 2. Hamlet and the Dream of Something After Death, By Julian C. Rice (pg. 109); "Thoughtful of the Main Chance ": Defoe and the cycle of Anxiety, By Toby A. Olshin (pg. 117); Sympathy for the Devil: A Dissenting View of Quilp, By Branwen B. Pratt (pg. 129); Henry James and Richard Wagner: The American, By Gary Lemco (pg. 147); Coming of Age in Mayo: Synge's Playboy of the Western World as a Rite of Passage, By Dbnald Gutierrez (pg. 159); The Function of Forgetting in Joyce's "Qay", By Robert J. Kloss (pg. 167); The Portrait of the Artist in Hesse's "Klein und Wagner", By Kurt J. Fickert (pg. 187); Of Kings and Machiavels, By Harry Rusche (pg. 188); The Psychological Fiction of Samuel Richardson, By Richard W. Noland (pg. 193).
  - Hartford Studies in Literature, Vol. 6, No. 3, 1974 (Object Bound book vol. 6-7, Box 1)
    Volume 6, Number 3. The Report of the Bedroom Scene in Sophocles' Oedipus, By Karl F. Harshbarger (pg. 197); Imaginary Voyages and Toy Novels, By Robert Plank (pg. 221); Historiographic and Literary: The Fusion of Two Eighteenth-Century Modes in Scott's Waverley, By H. G. Hahn (pg. 243); Psychoanalysis and Hamlet, By Richard W. Noland (pg. 268); Re Quilp: A Comment, By Michael Steig (pg. 282).
  - Hartford Studies in Literature, Vol. 7, No. 1, 1975 (Object Bound book vol. 6-7, Box 1)
    Volume 7, Number 1. THE ERIKSONIAN BILDUNGSROMAN; AN APPROACH THROUGH DORIS LESSING, By Ellen Cronan Rose (pg. 1); Preud and Aesthetics, By Richard W. Noland (pg. 18); Psychology and Fiction, By Richard W. Noland (pg. 26); Psychoanalysis and Yeats, By Richard W. Noland (pg. 33); Psychoanalytic Criticism: Past and Present, By Richard W. Noland (pg. 48); Scottish Ballad and Scottish Folk, By Virginia Shea Noto (pg. 59); "Madness" in Swift and Sterne, By Leo Rockas (pg. 67); Which One is Joyce?, By Paul H. Stacy (pg. 69); Excerpts from correspondence between Leonard, By Manheim and Mark Shechner (pg. 73); 1974 Bibliography on the Relations of Literature and the Other Arts (collected under the auspices of MLA Discussion Group General Topics IX) (pg. 77).
  - Hartford Studies in Literature, Vol. 7, No. 2, 1975 (Object Bound book vol. 6-7, Box 1)
    Volume 7, Number 2. FR21NKENSTEIN'S DREAM; THE CHILD AS FATHER OF THE MONSTER, By Gerhard Joseph (pg. 97); THE MONSTER WAS A LADY: ON THE PSYCHOLOGY OF MARY SHELLEY'S Frankenstein, By Gordon D. Hirsch (pg. 116); PERCEIVING AND CREATING IN INTERPRETATION, By Leon Waldoff (pg. 154); A NEW CRITICAL EPISTEMOLOGY, By Susan M. Elliott (pg. 170); A BOOK NOTE, By the Editor (pg. 190).
  - Hartford Studies in Literature, Vol. 7, No. 3, 1975 (Object Bound book vol. 6-7, Box 1)
    Volume 7, Number 3. ON DEATH AND DYING in Tolstoy's "THE DEATH OF IVAN ILYCH", By Hollis L. Gate (pg. 195); TOM AND OEDIPUS, By William Park (pg. 207); PSYCHOLOGY AND SYMBOL: CORRESPONDENCES BETWEEN HEART OF DARKNESS and DEATH IN VENICE, By Allan J. Mclntyre (pg. 216); Books Received (with comments by the Editor) (pg. 236); Journals (exchanges) received (pg. 241).
  - Hartford Studies in Literature, Vol. 8, No. 1, 1976 (Object Bound book vol. 8, Box 2)
    Volume 8, Number 1. INTRODUCTION TO THE SEMINAR, By Leonard Ft Manheim, Chairman (pg. 1); DICKENS AND FATHER: Notes on the Family Romance, By Branwen Bailey Pratt (pg. 4); PSYCHOANALYSIS AND BIOGRAPHY; DICKENS'EXPERIENCE AT WARREN'S BLACKING, By Albert D. Hutter (pg. 23); DICKENS' CHARACTERS AND PSYCHOANALYTIC CRITICISM, By Michael Steig (pg. 38); DISCUSSION NOTES, By Richard Dunn, Secretary of The Dickens Society (pg. 46); Mr. Dickens. & Dr. Elliotson, By Eugene F. Quirk (pg. 50).
  - Hartford Studies in Literature, Vol. 8, No. 2, 1976 (Object Bound book vol. 8, Box 2)
    Volume 8, Number 2. A NEW LOCK AT PANURGE, By Mary E. Ragland (pg. 61); TRIANGLES AND PRISONS: A STUDY OF STENDHALIAN LOVE, By Marilyn K. Yalom (pg. 82); PERSONALITY THEORY IN GIDE: THE PLUME OF THE EAGLE, By Diana Culbertson and John Valley (pg. 98); BRUCE MAZLISH AS PSYCHOHISTORIAN, By Richard W. Noland (pg. 116); 1975 Bibliography on the Relations of Literature and the Other Arts (collected under the auspices of MLA Discussion Group G. T. IX) (pg. 131).
  - Hartford Studies in Literature, Vol. 8, No. 3, 1976 (Object Bound book vol. 8, Box 2)
    Volume 8, Number 3. IMAGE MAKING; POLITICS AND CHARACTER DEVELOPMENT IN ALL THE KING'S MEN, By Dennis M. Welch (pg. 155); AMANDA STARR: VICTIM OF HER OWN FALSE ASSUMPTIONS, By Alma A. Ilacqua (pg. 178); INDIVIDUATION AND CHARACTER DEVELOPMENT IN THE FICTION OF SHIRLEY JACKSON, By Steven K. Hoffman (pg. 190); JOE CHRISTMAS: HIS TRAGEDY AS VICTIM, By Louise A. Poresky (pg. 209); THE METAPHYSICS OF YOKNAPATAWPHA COUNTY: "AIRY SPACE AND SCOPE FOR YOUR DELIRIUM", By Francine Ringold (pg. 223); PSYCHOANALYSIS BY "SCHOOLS", By Melvin Goldstein (pg. 241); THE WASHINGTON SCHOOL OF PSYCHIATRY PUBLISHES, By Marilyn K. Yalom (pg. 243); On Calvin S. Brown's A Glossary of Faulkner 's South, By Riva Ruran (pg. 245).
  - Hartford Studies in Literature, Vol. 9, No. 1, 1977 (Object Bound book vol. 9-10, Box 2)
    Volume 9, Number 1. David Copperfield: Novel and Film, By Ana Laura Zambrano (pg. 1); The Life and Adventures of Niaholas Nidkleby Alberto Cavalcanti Interprets Dickens, By David Paroissien (pg. 17); The Medium as Message in Bergman's Persona, By Julian C. Rice (pg. 29); The Impact of Music on the Eye, By Michael J. Queenan (pg. 45); On Appraising Erikson, By Richard W. Noland (pg. 48); Three Works of Victorian Social History, by John Morley (pg. 53); Ecologists, Humanists, and Parnassus; Or, Hitch Your Wagon To a Picaro, By William H. Plumstead (pg. 60); Valuable Content and Occasional Jargon, By Leo Rockas (pg. 64); Books Received (pg. 67); Journals (Exchanges) Received (pg. 76); Offprints Received (pg. 82).
  - University of Hartford Studies in Literature, Vol. 9, No. 2-3, 1977 (Object Bound book vol. 9-10, Box 2)
    Volume 9, Number 2 & 3. Law and Literature: Introduction and Application, By Richard Weisberg (pg. vi); Literature and the Law; An Interdisciplinary Liberal Arts Course, By Blair Rouse (pg. 83); The Law as "Father": An Aspect of the Dickens Pattern, By Leonard F. Manheim (pg. 100); Solzhenitsyn's View of Soviet Law in The First Circle, By Richard Weisberg (pg. 110); Jurisprudence in the Seventeenth Century From Manzoni's Viewpoint, By Jean-Pierre Barricelli (pg. 141); Law, Ritual, Absence: Towards A Semiology Of Law, By Richard Jacobson (pg. 164); Patrimony and Shakespeare's Daughters, By W. Nicholas Knight (pg. 175); Swift's Houyhnhms and Utopian Law, By Jerry Frese (pg. 187); Law and 'Heraldry' in Julius Caesar, By Robert F. Fleissner (pg. 196); Aspects of Law and Literature: The Revival and Search for Doctrine, By J. Allen Smith (pg. 213); The Novel as Art; Criticism as Illumination, By Branwen Bailey Pratt (pg. 223); Why an Abridgement?, By Ruth M. Wilson (pg. 232); New Solutions to Pinter's Puzzles, By Susan M. Elliott (pg. 237); Hidden Patterns II, By Leonard Tennenhouse (pg. 244).
  - University of Hartford Studies in Literature, Vol. 10, No. 1-3, 1978 (Object Bound book vol. 9-10, Box 2)
    Volume 10, Number 1, 2, 3. Introduction, BY LEONARD F. MANHEIM; M. D. FABER, AND HARVEY L. P. RESNIK (pg. 1); Prelude in Imperial Rome, The Son-Father Kills the Father-Son, Lucius Annaeus Seneca (4 B.C.? - 65 A.D.), BY M. D. FABER (pg. 14); Interlude in French Romanticism, Labrunie's Quest, Gerard de Nerval (1808- 1855), BY ELEANOR B. MANHEIM (pg. 31); The Twentieth Century in Great Britain and the USA, Creativity versus Death, Virginia Woolf (1882-1941), By SIMON O. LESSER (pg. 49); Symbolmaking and Suicide, Hart Crane (1899- 1932), BY DAVID BLEICH (pg. 70); An Author Wrecked by Success, Ross Lockridge, Jr. (1914 -1948), BY LEONARD F. MANHEIM (pg. 103); Say Goodbye to Randall J arrell (1914-1965), BY LOIS AND ALAN GORDON (pg. 122); Sylvia Plath and the Art of Dying Sylvia Plath (1932-1963), BY JEFFREY BERMAN (pg. 137); The Twentieth Century in Japan, A Koan of Sincerity, Osamu Dazai (1909 -1947), BY HIROSHI WAGATSUMA AND GEORGE DE VOS (pg. 156); The Mishima Incident, Yukio Mishima (1925 ? 1970), BY JAMES T. ARAKI (182)
  - University of Hartford Studies in Literature, Vol. 10, Supplement, 1978 (Object Bound book vol. 9-10, Box 2)
    Volume 10, Supplement. Books, Journals, and Offprints Received: Edward Klonoski, Assistant Editor (pg. 201); 1) Books received (pg. 201); 2) Journals (Exchanges) Received (pg. 215); 3) Single Issues and Offprints Received (pg. 222). Summary and Index: Margaret Rundle, Assistant Editor (pg. 226); 1) Summary (pg. 226); 2) Index to Volumes VI-X (pg. 229); a) Author-Title (List 1) (pg. 229); b) Subject (List 2) (pg. 238).
  - University of Hartford Studies in Literature, Vol. 11, No. 1, 1979 (Object Bound book vol. 11-12, Box 2)
    Volume 11, Number 1. Paranoia, Criticism, and Malvolio, By David Willbern (pg. 1); Prinary Process Mentation and the Structure of Timon of Athens, By Minerva Neiditz (pg. 24); "A Hair of the Shrew …", By Marion Perret (pg. 36); Games Courtiers Play, By Christine M. Bird (pg. 41); Drama of the Dying God in Julius Caesar, By Mildred Durham (pg. 49); The Basic Pattern of Psychological Conflict in Shakespearean Tragic Drama, By Joan Mary Byles (58); Article-Review: The Compleat Macbeth, By Barbara Hodgdon (pg. 72).
  - University of Hartford Studies in Literature, Vol. 11, No. 2, 1979 (Object Bound book vol. 11-12, Box 2)
    Volume 11, Number 2. The Theory of the Crisis of Generativity in Sophocles' Oedipus the King, By Richard W. Noland (pg. 83); The Napoleonic Era in Tolstoy's War and Peace and Zeranski's Ashes, By Zenon M. Kuk (pg. 94); The Autobiographical Heroine in Anna Karenina, By Doris v. Johnson (pg. 111); The "Economic" Problem in Proust and Freud, By Randolph Splitter (pg. 123); Explicating Jacques Lacan: An overview, By Ellie Ragland-Sullivan (pg. 140).
  - University of Hartford Studies in Literature, Vol. 11, No. 3, 1979 (Object Bound book vol. 11-12, Box 2)
    Volume 11, Number 3. Swinburne, Hopkins, and the Roots of Modernism, By Robert C. Schweìk (pg. 157); George Herbert and the Man of Sorrows, By John Bienz (pg. 173); The Dream Merchants: Musicians in Madame Bovary, By Rita S. Mall (pg. 185); Malignant Fires and the Chain of Jealousy: Blake's Treatment of Oedipal Conflict, By Diana Hume George (pg. 197); Picturesque Satire in Little Dorrit, By Nancy K. Hill (pg. 212); Dickens Phiz, By John R. Reed (pg. 224); Books Received (pg. 229).
  - University of Hartford Studies in Literature, Vol. 12, No. 1, 1980 (Object Bound book vol. 11-12, Box 2)
    Volume 12, Number 1. Doubling and Sexual Identity in Stories by Franz Kafka, By Sammy McLean (pg. 1); The Experience of Old Age in Contemporary Autobiography, By Celeste Loughman (pg. 18); The Secret of Aiken's Snow, By Robert Kloss (pg. 29); Samuel Johnson's Case History of Richard Savage, By Gloria Sybil Gross (pg. 39); Final Harvest, By William Stull (pg. 48); Psychoanalysis, Dostoevsky, and The Idiot, By Robert Rogers (pg. 55); Metaphor: The Dynamics of Reader Response, By Charles L. Ross (pg. 59); Literary Mysteries, By Virginia Hale (pg. 64); Journals and Offprints Received Prepared with the assistance of Dan Stark and Charles Lipka (pg. 66).
  - University of Hartford Studies in Literature, Vol. 12, No. 2, 1980 (Object Bound book vol. 11-12, Box 2)